<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Shyam Ramakrishnan</title>
    <link>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Shyam Ramakrishnan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Hi! I am pursuing a Master&amp;rsquo;s in Computer Science at North Carolina State University, Raleigh. My interests include cloud computing, machine learning, front end development and software practices in continuous deployment and configuration management.
Besides academics, playing guitar and exploring different guitar gears are among my passions. I also love soccer and have played competitive soccer in local leagues.
Curriculum Vitae</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skills</title>
      <link>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/skills/</guid>
      <description>Languages: Java, Python, C#, R
Web Technologies: Spring MVC, Node.js, AngularJS, ASP.NET MVC, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Ajax, Bootstrap
Database Technologies: MS SQL, MySQL, Oracle 11g, Apache Cassandra
Tools and Utilities: Ansible, Docker, Maven, Jenkins, Travis CI, DataDog, Prometheus, ElasticSearch, Logstash, Kibana, Grafana, Amazon AWS, Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Tensorflow
Operating Systems: Mac OS, Windows, Linux
Testing: JUnit, Selenium, Capybara, Nock, Mockito</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Experience</title>
      <link>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/experience/</guid>
      <description>Software Engineering Intern
Cisco Systems, Research Triangle Park (May 2017 - Aug 2017)
 Worked with the Cloud Collaboration team to Implement Cisco Spark call failure analysis using machine learning
 Built a GPU server and setup the model training and prediction workflows to perform real time call failure classification
 Worked on troubleshooting issues, bug fixes, automation scripts and REST API performance tests for Cisco Spark Call
 Technologies used include Linux Bash, Python, Docker, ElasticSearch, Kibana, Apache Spark, Maven, Cassandra</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/projects/</guid>
      <description>Slack DevOps Chat Bot - VMOps
Using Node.js, Vagrant, Ansible, Amazon AWS, CloudWatch
 Developed a conversational slack bot to configure and manage remote virtual machines on AWS servers using Ansible
 Implemented features for users to spin up VMs, monitor resource utilization, merge VMs and shrink VM resources
  Performance Analysis of Containers and VMs for Cloud Applications
Using Docker, VirtualBox, Grafana, OpenNMS
 Analyzed performance of Docker containers vs Type 2 hypervisor based VMs for compute and data centric cloud apps</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other</title>
      <link>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/works/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/works/</guid>
      <description>Achievements:
 Achieved a jury award for Second position at LexisNexis Rise to Code Hackathon - Raleigh, Oct 2017
 Certificate of Excellence on client nomination at Tata Consultancy Services for proficient application development - Mumbai, Feb 2016, Client: ABN Amro Bank NV  Part Time Internship:
 Was selected as a Student Developer Intern in 2017 Programme Management Lite Internship with the Office of Information Technology at NCSU
 Worked with the Identity and Access Management team and implemented Oracle Identity Manager system</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shyam-ramakrishnan.github.io/home/contact/</guid>
      <description>If you have an interesting project or an opportunity, please connect with me on LinkedIn or send me an email.
 Shyam Ramakrishnan </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>